We'll have the invocation by the
Soppel's Minister for First Christian Church, Mr.
Brandon Butler.
Paul again, we love you.
We're thankful for this chance.
It's a come together as a community, as leaders in the community,
and try to serve this community well.
God, I just pray that you would be with every decision made tonight.
It may be in the best interest of everybody involved and further
grow-offs as the city of Miami.
God, again, we thank you.
We assess that.
And more like Jesus, today's name we pray.
Amen.
Four public inputters on schedule personal appearances.
Five considered gender staff recommends we approve item six and seven.
Eight.
Gidel Stratton claim for Pensacola J. R. D. A.
Realizes in the amount of $645.
August 24th on behalf of the city.
Primarily, this time, they spent dealing with
five matters in reviewing a FERC filing and a GRDA permit filing
and answering some citizen questions.
Any questions?
There you go.
Nine. Service Regiment of Tyler Technologies Incorporated.
To migrate the cities, financial software,
income, to Tyler Technologies Cloud and Environment amount of $106,428.
Let's just keep those.
Evening everybody.
So, income is what customer service uses for utility
accounts and utility building and is owned by Tyler Technologies.
The servers that we have once sight currently are in
the life.
And we have two options.
Either rebuild the servers or migrate the data to Tyler Technologies
Cloud Environment.
It's going to be 160,000 overall.
If we were to rebuild the servers that have an engineer come to train
migrate the data once sight.
It's going to be about 85,000.
If we move it to their cloud, we don't have to eat that cost every five to seven years of making
servers and their security when they're in on a cloud environment is better than stop
not.
So we should be fine there if we have any issues.
That was the money coming from, good to you as much as you can.
This gets a completely away from encode.
Doesn't get us away from encode.
It gets us away from housing encode on site here.
Yeah.
So I don't think of what happened, but we are doing something different to try to stop that
from happening as well.
This also increases accessibility as currently if you are offsite and you need to get into
encode or if you are bow, you have to remote in to see our stuff.
This will make it a web-based so anybody can see it when they need to if they are home.
So you talked about security a second ago.
There's so with it being a remote, the payload is there potential for a fax and thing like that.
I mean there's always a potential for a fax, but we need to protect ourselves from those.
So currently we have our firewalls and our anti-virus in place to stop anything we do monthly
trainings to stop fishing.
We move the data to their cloud.
It will be encrypted at rest and when we are using it and so that will help there.
And if we do get breached, the data will not be here to be that so we are covered in that aspect
as well.
You go back up now.
We do incremental backups every nine and full backups every weekend.
Is that a negative cloud, is that?
Yes, sir.
That's a party cloud vendor called United's Global.
So then you no longer have to do those backups physically?
Not for that.
And that will save us prices or our costs are as well because they charge per gig.
So we'll have to back up four servers instead of two but if we migrate the data then we just
lose two altogether.
So I honestly don't.
I'll top my list.
What would you say it was to redo the current service?
Roughly 85,000.
Now our yearly cost of licensing and maintenance will go up to 100,000 compared to the 70.
70 that it is now, but long term we will be able to, they are going to merge their
newest version of encode with the version that we use now and we should get that up.
for free, which currently it is very substantial.
Thank you.
Number 10, award-bed C22-45 for construction of a sludge storage building to these concrete
construction.
A proof contract continued upon this admission of required contract documents and approved
the city manager or his design need to sign notice to proceed, Mr. Todd Murphy.
Yes.
I want to give you guys a little bit of history about the plant.
And I'll kind of explain why I'm asking for this building.
The first, the pictures I put in your packet, if you look at the one, not the one with
the tractor but the other one, the one that has that wall, that area right there is where,
right now when we press our sludge, it dumps into this area.
That area was not designed for storage when they built this plant.
What it was designed for was to put one of them row off dumpsters under there and then it just
fall into the dumpster and it would haul it to the landfill.
Well, the problem with the landfill was it was real expensive so we wanted to find another option.
We'll work class B sludge so there was only two other options.
One was incinerated, which wasn't an option for us because we checked those down years ago, and
the other one was land application.
So we found some land, got it approved through DEQ, right now we got 12 acres out by the
O-Train Bridge with a lagoon lift station and that's where we take this stuff you see
piled up here, it's called Bialisolans, it's a biological solid that we loaded up and trucks
and take it out there and spread it on the ground and then disk it in.
Well, the problem with land application is when it's, we're wet and rain in all the time, you
can't get out there, you can't put them big trucks out there across that property so you see what
it does, it piles up in here.
So if you look at the other picture, the one with the tractor and that's after we've loaded it up
and hauled it off and you can see the nasty mess that that stuff makes because it's getting rain
to on this, this is open to the elements here and it's getting rain to on.
So this new storage building would do a couple of things for us, give us a storage we need and
it also keeps this stuff out of the rain but we want to go a little bit further than that with it.
If you guys approve the building and if we get a build, we want to add heat lamps to it to
dry it out further so it'll be even more easier for us to handle and then also it'll do one
other thing.
That side out there we have.
the living side. Well, only last about eight or 10 more years. That's based on the level of
metals that you put on it. If we dry this stuff more, it'll shrink it because it's even coming
off the bed at 80% water, so it'll shrink up a whole lot. So we won't have to haul it off instead of
hauling over six times a year. We may haul two or three times a year. So now our landslide will
last maybe 20 or 25 years. So that's the reason I'm asking for this. So I talked to Bo about this
a little bit. I know Bo's excited about it, so let's go ahead, Bo.
I am. I think this is brilliant. I would never thought about this to me probably over a year ago.
He wanted to see if we could start looking at how we could include this in our future budget,
because it's something he's been wanting to do in researching for quite a while. And, you know,
honestly, guys, I think this is something that we're going to have other communities coming
to us wanting to tour what talks are doing and learn how he's doing it, because this just makes perfect
sense. There is one other element. I wasn't going to bring this up there, but there is one other thing
if it works, it'll be really, really good for the city. If we dry that enough, and that heat will kill the
color form. So I said to this was a class B sludge. If we can get it to a class A sludge, we don't need
to land them, or we don't need to decide, we don't have to take care of it. We can just give it away.
But that would be a big challenge for me to get that proof to DQ that it's a class A,
but that's one of the things that I want to try to do. What's that?
He left you said was a, I heard you said I'm an additive. Was this all else again?
You mean this area here?
Well, I'll talk about it. I'll talk about it. I'll talk about it.
Either heat lamps are going to be an additional cost or what the price isn't here.
The lamps are going to be an additional cost, sorry. There'll be a additional cost. There'll be about 20,000
for all of them. And you said this building is budgeted. How long will it take to build this building
start to finish? Well, I talked to Zab today, since he was the one that got it. And he said,
the first thing you wanted to do is get all the materials ordered and then wait to see what kind of issue
that's going to be with, you know, was it having a metal roof and all that, you know, things are so hard to get
now days. So, it's kind of hard to tell, but he's wanting to get on it pretty quick.
So when do you think it be a completion date ballpark I'm hoping it's like I think once he starts. I'm hoping it's four or five months
So four five months, so we have the extra 20 or 30 he needs for a lot of the heat lamp
Could we include that in this year's budget?
Yeah, we've got it
So they already budgeted as well
As far as you know, it's just being done anywhere else in the state now there's there's other types of ways to dry it
But they're in the me and dollar range. I didn't really want to come to you guys and ask for that
We thank you for that
Well before we go I think I'd like to say you know, I kind of thought about this. You know, we got employees out there that are thinking in ways to save
the community money
Then we need to give them a shot we need to give them a chance to succeed with this and I know he's put a lot into this a lot of thought in this
And if we do this and other employees see that they may come forward with some ideas
But their jobs that may save us some money. So I like to fact the top put this effort into it. So I'll make a push ahead. Thank you
Second
Thanks talk 11 other new business of any which is a residence since the posting of this agenda
12 staff reports
13 trustee community announcements
14 this meeting will be continued from the council chambers and we convened in the staff room for the purpose of the exact